<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XenonMKV>
  <strings>
    <string id="Application_Loaded">XenonMKV build {0} ({1}) started.</string>
    <string id="Application_NextItem">Processing next MKV file in queue.</string>
    <string id="Application_NoMoreItems">No more MKV files in queue to process.</string>
    
    <string id="DetermineFileSplit_Required">The selected file will be split. You can change this setting in Tools/Options/File Splitting.</string>
    <string id="DetermineFileSplit_SizeInfo">{0} is ~{1} MiB.</string>

    <string id="AddFile_Single">Processing file: {0}.</string>
    <string id="AddFile_FromFolder">Processing file in batch: {0}.</string>

    <string id="StartConvert_File">Starting conversion process for {0}.</string>

    <string id="MKVInfo_Start">Retrieving MKV information.</string>
    <string id="MKVSplit_Start">Checking whether the MKV file needs to be split.</string>
    <string id="MKVSplit_UserDeny">{0} will not be split due to user preference.</string>
    <string id="MKVSplit_FileSize">{0} is ~{1} MiB.</string>
    <string id="MKVSplit_SplitFilePieces">Splitting file to {0} pieces of ~{1} MiB.</string>
    <string id="MKVSplit_NoSplitThreshold">Not splitting file, since it is under {0} MiB.</string>

    <string id="MKVSplit_Cutoff_Start">Splitting file and cutting off video at {0} seconds.</string>
    <string id="MKVSplit_Cutoff_Cancel">[E]Video cutoff process cancelled. Aborting conversion.</string>

    <string id="MKVParse_VideoFPS">Detected a video track with {0} frames per second.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_Length">Length of MKV file is ~{0} seconds.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_CodecID">Detected video or audio codec: {0}.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_TrackDetails">Using track {0} ({1}) for video and track {2} ({3}) for audio.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_VideoDimensions">Video dimensions (width x height) are {0} x {1}.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_VideoDAR">Video display aspect ratio (DAR) is {0}.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_VideoPAR">Video pixel aspect ratio (PAR) is {0}.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_VideoPARRoundUp">Rounding up the pixel aspect ratio from {0} to 1:1.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_VideoPARRoundDown">Rounding down the pixel aspect ratio from {0} to 1:1.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_CustomARSet">Custom display aspect ratio (DAR) of {0} set.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_AllTracksAdded">All tracks from MKV file were detected.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_MultiMKVSet">This MKV file is part of a split set. Using track selections from the first item.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_AutoTrackSel">Automatically selecting video and audio tracks from the MKV file.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_MultiAVTracks">This MKV file contains multiple video or audio tracks. Displaying track selection dialog.</string>
    <string id="MKVParse_SingleAVTrack">This MKV file contains one audio and one video track.</string>

    <string id="MKVExtract_Start">[W]Demuxing the MKV file into video and audio tracks.</string>
    <string id="MKVMerge_SafeSync">[E]This MKV file appears to have synchronization problems. You may want to try enabling safe synchronization in Tools/Options/Tracks.</string>

    <string id="HexEdit_Success">[A]Changed video bit from AVC 5.1 profile to AVC 4.1 profile.</string>

    <string id="Azid_Start">[W]Starting Azid AC3 decoder to create a WAV file.</string>
    <string id="FFmpeg_Start">[W]Starting FFmpeg decoder to create a WAV file.</string>
    <string id="Valdec_Start">[W]Starting AC3Filter/valdec to create a WAV file.</string>

    <string id="mplayer_Start">[W]Using mplayer to create a 2-channel WAV file.</string>
    <string id="eac3to_Start">[W]Using eac3to, which may take 15-20 minutes without progress. Anything longer and there's been a problem.</string>

    <string id="NeroAAC_Params">Initializing Nero AAC encoder with quality parameters: {0} {1}</string>
    <string id="NeroAAC_Start">[W]Using Nero to convert WAV to 2-channel AAC. (This might take a while to get started.)</string>

    <string id="MP4Box_Start">[W]Generating MP4 file from x264 video and 2-channel AAC.</string>
    <string id="MP4Box_Start_044">[W]Using mp4box version 0.4.4 (stable, June 3 2007) to generate file.</string>
    <string id="MP4Box_Start_default">[W]Using mp4box version 0.4.6 rev2125 (default, Oct 18 2010) to generate file.</string>
    <string id="MP4Box_Start_20080413">[W]Using mp4box version 0.4.5-dev (April 2008) to generate file.</string>
    <string id="MP4Tags_Start">[W]Tagging MP4 file with title {0} for Xbox 360 display.</string>

    <string id="Finish_ConversionComplete">[A]Conversion complete.</string>
    <string id="Finish_ConversionMoveOK">[A]Conversion complete. Your MP4 file has been moved to the destination folder.</string>
    <string id="Finish_ConversionMoveFail">[E]Conversion complete for {0}, but the file could not be moved from {1}.</string>
    <string id="Finish_ConversionMoveNA">Conversion complete. Please rename or move output.mp4 from your scratch folder to continue.{\n}{\n}(This message is appearing because you have the Tools / Move Output File option unchecked.)</string>
    <string id="Finish_ConversionMoveNATitle">Conversion Complete - Move Output File</string>

    <string id="CancelProcess">[E]Cancelled conversion process.</string>
  </strings>

  <error_strings>
    <string id="Error_ExceptionFollows">[E]An exception occurred (please report this issue) : </string>
    <string id="Error_GeneralConversion">[E]Conversion process aborted due to an error.</string>
    <string id="Error_CreateTempOutputFolder">[E]Could not create temporary output folder {0}. Cancelling conversion.</string>
    <string id="Error_FileNotFound">[E]File not found for conversion: {0}.</string>
    <string id="Error_NoAVID">[E]Could not retrieve video or audio track from the MKV file. (A: {0} V: {1})</string>
    <string id="Error_UnknownCodec">[E]Unrecognized codec {0}.</string>
    <string id="Error_ProcessStartFNF">[E]Could not find tool to launch: {0}.</string>
    
    <string id="Error_ConvertAR">[E]Could not convert the display aspect ratio {0}. Using 1:1 ratio.</string>
    <string id="Error_ParseAR">[E]An error occurred parsing the display aspect ratio: {0}</string>

    <string id="Error_ReferenceFramesExceeded">[E]This video file will not be compatible with the Xbox 360 as it contains too many reference frames. Cancelling conversion.</string>
    <string id="Warning_ReferenceFramesExceeded">[W]This video file will not be compatible with the Xbox 360 as it contains too many reference frames. Continuing conversion.</string>

    <string id="Error_TrackSelCancel">[E]Track selection cancelled.</string>

    <string id="Error_HexEditFail">[E]Could not properly hex edit the video file. Video extraction is likely incomplete.</string>
    <string id="Error_HexEditFNF">[E]The extracted video file was not found.</string>
    <string id="Error_HexEditAccess">[E]The extracted video file could not be accessed.</string>
    <string id="Error_HexEditIO">[E]The extracted video file could not be written to. Details follow: </string>

    <string id="Error_EAC3To_Fail">[E]EAC3To did not convert the audio properly.</string>
    <string id="Error_FFmpeg_Fail">[E]FFmpeg did not convert the audio properly.</string>
    <string id="Error_EAC3To_Nero7">[E]The fallback eac3to utility requires a full Nero 7 installation. Could not convert audio.</string>
    <string id="Error_AudioFallback">[E]The conversion process did not produce any audio. Falling back to eac3to.</string>
    <string id="Error_mplayer_AudioFallback">[E]mplayer could not read the audio file properly. Falling back to eac3to.</string>

    <string id="Error_MP4Box_VideoFNE">[E]The video does not exist in the scratch folder. This may be a bug in XenonMKV. Please report this issue.</string>

    <string id="Error_MP4Box_Fail">[W]mp4box has failed to convert your files. Falling back to version 0.4.4 to run conversion.</string>
    <string id="Error_MP4Box_Fail2">[E]mp4box version 0.4.4 has failed to convert your file. Please view log_output.txt in the XenonMKV directory for details, and report this issue to the support forums.</string>

    <string id="Error_InputFileInvalid">Please select a valid MKV file to convert.</string>
    <string id="Error_InputFolderInvalid">Please select a valid folder to convert from.</string>
    <string id="Error_OutputFolderNetwork">Input and output locations must be located on a local disk or mapped network drive.</string>
    <string id="Error_OutputFolderInvalid">Please specify a valid output folder.</string>
    <string id="Error_FreeSpaceOutput">Not enough space on drive {0} to convert file. (Three times its size needs to be free.)</string>
    <string id="Error_FreeSpaceScratch">Not enough space in scratch folder on drive {0} to convert file. (Three times its size needs to be free.)</string>
    <string id="Error_InvalidScratch">No scratch folder set. Temporary files will be stored in {0}. Use Tools/Options to change.</string>

    <string id="Error_DTSDecodeSync">A possible sync error occurred when decoding DTS audio. Please verify the source and output files.</string>

    <string id="Error_NoAudioCodec">Audio codec could not be detected. This may be a bug in XenonMKV. Please report this issue.</string>
  </error_strings>

  <options_strings>
    <string id="ScratchFolder_Network">The selected scratch folder is a network location. This will unreasonably reduce XenonMKV performance.
    {\n}Please select another scratch folder or use the default setting.</string>
    <string id="ScratchFolder_Network_Title">Network Location Selected</string>
    <string id="ScratchFolder_NotExist">The selected scratch folder does not exist.</string>
    <string id="ScratchFolder_NotExist_Title">Invalid Scratch Folder</string>
    <string id="ScratchFolder_NotWritable">The selected scratch folder cannot be written to.</string>
    <string id="ScratchFolder_NotWritable_Title">Invalid Scratch Folder</string>
  </options_strings>

  <ui_strings>
    <string id="UI_Title">XenonMKV build {0} ({1})</string>
    
    <string id="UI_About_Title">About XenonMKV</string>
    <string id="UI_About_DevCredits">XenonMKV is developed by Jake Billo, Bill Robertson, and other community contributors.</string>
    <string id="UI_About_CreditIcons">Some icons used under Creative Commons Attribution License from famfamfam.com.</string>
    <string id="UI_About_CreditLinkText">Visit site</string>
    <string id="UI_About_GPL">This program is made available under the GNU GPL 2.0. Please view README.txt and gpl.txt for more details.</string>
    <string id="UI_About_CloseButton">Close</string>

    <string id="UI_TimeSplit_OKNoSplit">Don't Split</string>
    <string id="UI_TimeSplit_OK">OK</string>

    <string id="UI_SelTrack_Title">Select Video and Audio Tracks</string>
    
    <string id="UI_SourceFolder">Input folder: </string>
    <string id="UI_SourceSingle">Single MKV file: </string>

    <string id="UI_ConvertSingle">Convert single file</string>
    <string id="UI_ConvertFolder">Convert a folder</string>

    <string id="UI_OutputFolderBrowser_Desc">Select the folder to place the converted MP4 file(s).</string>
    <string id="UI_InputFolderBrowser_Desc">Select the folder to read the original MKV file(s) from.</string>
    <string id="UI_InputFileBrowser_Filter">MKV Files (*.mkv)|*.mkv</string>

    <string id="UI_ToolsMenu">Tools</string>
    <string id="UI_Tools_MKVInformation">MKV Information</string>
    <string id="UI_Tools_MKVInformation_Error">Please select a single, valid MKV file before choosing this option.</string>
    <string id="UI_Tools_EnableMP4Playback">Enable .mp4 in Media Player</string>
    <string id="UI_Tools_Options">Options</string>

    <string id="UI_HelpMenu">Help</string>
    <string id="UI_Help_Website">Website</string>
    <string id="UI_Help_Forum">Forum</string>
    <string id="UI_Help_About">About</string>

    <string id="UI_ShowToolOutput">Log all tool output</string>
    <string id="UI_ScrollLog">Scroll log</string>

    <string id="UI_CancelProcessButton">Cancel</string>
    <string id="UI_StartRecodeButton">Start</string>

    <string id="UI_MP4SupportAgain">MP4 support already appears to be enabled. Run the support registry patch again?</string>
    <string id="UI_MP4SupportAgain_Title">Reapply MP4 Registry Patch?</string>
    <string id="UI_MP4SupportSuccess">MP4 playback is now enabled in Windows Media Player.</string>
    <string id="UI_MP4SupportSuccess_Title">MP4 Playback Enabled</string>

    <string id="UI_ProvideARDesc">The display aspect ratio (DAR) for this file was detected as {0}. You can override this value if needed.</string>
    <string id="UI_CustomAR_Fail">The display aspect ratio provided ({0}) was invalid. Please enter a decimal number or ratio such as 16:9.</string>
    <string id="UI_CustomAR_FailTitle">Invalid Display Aspect Ratio</string>

    <string id="UI_Tray_Title">XenonMKV</string>
    <string id="UI_Tray_Success">All MKV files have been converted.</string>

    <string id="UI_Options_RestartApp">You will need to restart XenonMKV for your changes to take effect.</string>
    
    <string id="UI_Options_TargetBitrateNonNumeric">Only numeric values are allowed for target bitrates.</string>
    <string id="UI_Options_TargetBitrateNonNumericTitle">Numeric Value Required</string>

    <string id="UI_Options_ScratchFolderNotExist">The scratch folder specified does not exist or is not writable. The scratch folder will be reset to the default location.</string>
    <string id="UI_Options_ScratchFolderNoUNC">You cannot use a network path for the scratch folder. The scratch folder will be reset to the default location.</string>

    <string id="ToolTip_PreviewMedia_1">Preview the selected media file in the default player.</string>
    <string id="ToolTip_PreviewMedia_M">Open the selected media folder.</string>
    <string id="ToolTip_BrowseOutputFolder">Browse for an output folder for the MP4 files.</string>
    <string id="ToolTip_BrowseInputSource">Browse for an MKV file or folder containing MKV files.</string>
    <string id="ToolTip_ViewOutputFolder">View the contents of the selected output folder.</string>

    <string id="Info_AzidDRC">This option sets the overall dynamic compression in the decoder. This value is applied to every output speaker.
    
The bitstream contains information of how much to amplify or attenuate the sound to decrease the overall dynamic variations (loudness) in the program contents. 

Different options exists to choose the wanted dynamic reduction:


o none     No dynamic compression. The program contents is unchanged.

o normal   Normal dynamic compression. Normal in-store decoders use this as an hardcoded default.

o light    Light dynamic compression. This is 50% (-6db) of the reduction/gain that normal dynamic compression would give.

o heavy    Heavy dynamic compression. Intended for poor listening environment with much background noise.

o inverse  Dynamic expansion. This is the inverse value of the light dynamic compression, i.e. it makes strong sounds stronger and weaker sounds weaker.</string>
    <string id="Info_AzidRearFilter">This option controls rear-channel filtering in 2/0 output mode. The
      filter is a 2nd order Butterworth filter with at -3 dB point at 7
      kHz. There are two major applications for this feature:

      o To provide proper Pro Logic downmix of the rear channels

      o Phasing-problems in the downmix (washy sound) caused by the rear
      channel downmix into the L R channels.

      Usually the rear channels are phased 90 deg in respect of the front
      channels prior or inside the ac3 encoder. This is done to avoid
      phasing problems when downmixing the program contents to two
      channels. Some sources do not provide this shifting, and thus this
      feature is added.

      The filter provides an increasing phase shift according to
      frequency. It is 90 deg at 7kHz.</string>
    <string id="Info_AzidDialogNormalization">
      This selects if the decoder should use dialog normalization
      reduction. The normal dialogue level in a program is defined a
      reference of loudness, 0db.  The BSI info variable "dialogue level"
      informs how much this dialogue level is under 0db full-scale (FS) - or
      how much headroom there is above the dialogue level before clip.

      One of Dolby's intentions with this variable is to ensure that all
      dialogue levels are played back with the same volume, regardless of
      the program's amount of headroom. It is good to have when the movie
      you're looking at is interrupted by a commercial break, where the
      headroom varies enormously.  (It prevents blowing your ears off when
      the break comes.)

      This feature is implemented by attenuate everything such that all
      programs have 31 db headroom, regardless of its original headroom. For
      a typical -27db headroom program, this will case a -4db gain.
    </string>
    <string id="Info_AzidStereoDownmix">
      When 2/0 decoding is selected, this option controls what kind of
      stereo downmix should be applied. Possible values are:

      o mono. Used for mono downmixes

      o stereo. Standard stereo downmix

      o dpl (default). Dolby Pro Logic downmix is selected

      o dplii. The new Dolby Pro Logic II downmix is selected
    </string>
    
  </ui_strings>

  <update_strings>
    <string id="Update_Failed">XenonMKV could not check for updates. Please ensure you are connected to the Internet. The XenonMKV site may also be down; in this case, please try again later.</string>
    <string id="Update_Failed_Title">Update Process Unsuccessful</string>

    <string id="Update_Available">An update to XenonMKV is available. The new version is {0} and you are currently running version {1}. Would you like to download the new version?</string>
    <string id="Update_Available_Title">Update Available</string>

    <string id="Update_NotAvailable">No updates to XenonMKV are available. (The latest public release is version {0} and you are currently running version {1}.){\n} Please check back at a later date.</string>
    <string id="Update_NotAvailable_Title">No Update Available</string>
  </update_strings>

  <debug_strings>
    <string id="DEBUG_FileNotFound">(FileNotFoundException) File not found: {0}. Please report this error at the XenonMKV forum.
    
    In the meantime, you can try unchecking the Tools / Move Final File option and rerunning the conversion, then moving output.mp4 from your scratch folder manually.</string>
    <string id="DEBUG_InvalidPath">(ArgumentException) Invalid path to file: {0}. Please report this error at the XenonMKV forum.</string>
    <string id="DEBUG_NullPath">(ArgumentNullException) Path or destination is blank: {0} Please report this error at the XenonMKV forum.</string>
    <string id="DEBUG_IOException">(IOException) I/O error accessing or moving file: {0}{\n}{1} Please report this error at the XenonMKV forum.</string>
    <string id="DEBUG_NotSupported">(NotSupportedException) Invalid path format: {0} Please report this error at the XenonMKV forum.</string>
    <string id="DEBUG_Cancelled">(OperationCancelledException) Operation cancelled by user. Please report this error at the XenonMKV forum.</string>
    <string id="DEBUG_Security">(SecurityException) User does not have permissions to view path: {0}{\n}{1} Please report this error at the XenonMKV forum.</string>
    <string id="DEBUG_Unauthorized">(UnauthorizedAccessException) User does not have access to view path: {0}{\n}{1} Please report this error at the XenonMKV forum.</string>
  </debug_strings>
</XenonMKV>